Guide to the Collège de la Sainte Famille Collection AD.MC.028
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- School event. 8.8 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1381)
  Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Microphones; Schools/Education; Nuns; Men; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Bags/Purses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Events/Occasions; Religious Crosses
- School teacher(?) talking on the phone. 7.3 x 10.3 cm, 1958 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1382)
  Telephones; Photographic Prints; Men; Helwan, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Priests/Clergymen; Books; Gelatin Silver Prints
- The Sainte Famille church. 9 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1383)
  Churches; Architecture; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Streets/Roads
- Students exercising in school. 8.9 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1384)
  Sports; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Students; Helwan, Egypt; Girls; Boys; Children; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Students exercising in school. 9 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1385)
  Schools/Education; Students; Sports; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Students exercising in school. 9 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1386)
  Photographic Prints; Students; Helwan, Egypt; Sports; Schools/Education; Students; Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Students exercising in school. 9 x 14 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1387)
- A portrait of one of the school's clergymen. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1388)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Priests/Clergymen; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Class portrait. 8.8 x 14 cm, 1954-1955 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1389)
  Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Teachers; Boys; Men; Students; Italian Writing; Children; Priests/Clergymen; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- School year group portrait. 10 x 15 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1390)
  Priests/Clergymen; Italian Writing; Men; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Teachers; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Students; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Schools/Education; Girls
- Class portrait. 10 x 15.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1391)
  Men; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Children; Schools/Education; Teachers; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Students
- Class portrait. 10.1 x 15 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1392)
  Men; Group Portraits; Teachers; Women; Students; Schools/Education; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Children; Priests/Clergymen; Color Photography
- Class portrait. 10.1 x 15.1 cm, 1960/1970 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1393)
  Children; Color Photography; Group Portraits; Teachers; Students; Schools/Education; Helwan, Egypt; Boys; Photographic Prints; Priests/Clergymen; Men
- Class portrait. 9.8 x 15.1 cm, 1960/1970 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1394)
  Women; Men; Teachers; Color Photography; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Boys; Students; Priests/Clergymen; Helwan, Egypt; Children; Schools/Education
- Class portrait. 10 x 15.2 cm, 1960/1970 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1395)
  Color Photography; Men; Group Portraits; Schools/Education; Children; Teachers; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Students; Boys; Helwan, Egypt
- A group of men, nuns and clergymen in a house. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1397)
  Houses; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Men; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nuns; Tiles; Women; Priests/Clergymen; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Religious Crosses
- Two men looking a camera. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1398)
  Italian Writing; Priests/Clergymen; Men; Photographic Prints; Cameras; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Entrance of a family tomb (dating to 1879). 14.5 x 10.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1399)
  Cairo, Egypt; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Buildings; Helwan, Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Color Photography; Cemeteries; Religious Crosses; Color Photography
- Document in Italian about Daniele Comboni. 29.7 x 19.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1400)
  Italian Writing; Printed Materials; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints
- Airmail envelope containing a copy of a letter (dating to 14/2/1879). 10.4 x 14.6 cm, 20 February 1991 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1401)
  Printed Materials; Photographic Prints; Postcards; Italian Writing; Signatures; Helwan, Egypt; Printed Materials
- Letter about a tomb affiliated with a Catholic mission to Egypt. 29.7 x 20.4 cm, 14 February 1879 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1402)
  Italian Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Printed Materials; Signatures; Medals/Insignia
- Entrance of a family tomb. 14.5 x 10.1 cm, 1879 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1403)
  Color Photography; Architecture; Tombs/Mausoleums; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Buildings
- A family tomb. 14.5 x 10.1 cm, 1879 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1404)
  Architecture; Tombs/Mausoleums; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Color Photography
- Construction in front of a family tomb. 14.6 x 10.1 cm, 1879 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1405)
  Color Photography; Tombs/Mausoleums; Construction; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Cemetery. 10.1 x 14.5 cm, 1879 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1406)
  Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Color Photography; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- Family tombs in a cemetery (dating back to 1879). 14.5 x 10.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1407)
  Cemeteries; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Color Photography; Tombs/Mausoleums; Helwan, Egypt; Religious Sites
- The interior of a family tomb (dating back to 1879). 14.5 x 10.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1408)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Color Photography; Italian Writing; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Religious Sites
- Wedding ceremony in a church. 10.1 x 15.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1409)
  Women; Color Photography; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Weddings; Girls; Churches; Weddings; Religious Imagery; Religious Sites; Children
- Man with a young woman in a house. 15.2 x 9.8 cm, 2003 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1410)
  Color Photography; Weddings; Furnishings; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Helwan, Egypt
- Two women with an infant. 10.2 x 15.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1411)
  Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Children; Women; Color Photography; Group Portraits
- Two men and a woman. 9.8 x 15.1 cm, 2003 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1412)
  Computers; Group Portraits; Men; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Women; Helwan, Egypt; Color Photography
- Photo of two men in a house. 9.8 x 15.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1413)
  Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Color Photography; Men; Helwan, Egypt
- Two men and a woman. 9.8 x 15.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1414)
  Photographic Prints; Women; Helwan, Egypt; Italian Writing; Computers; Color Photography; Men; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- A portrait. 9.8 x 15.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1415)
  Hats; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Helwan, Egypt; Color Photography
- School hall with framed photographs lining the wall. 8.9 x 12.6 cm, 1987-1988 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1417)
  Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Color Photography; Schools/Education; Italian Writing; Furnishings
- A framed map of Egypt. 12.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1418)
  Maps; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Schools/Education; Color Photography
- Map of the Royal Excavations at Helwan (Ezbet el Walda). 8.9 x 12.6 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1423)
  Italian Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Arabic Writing; Maps; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Color Photography
- Historical map. 8.9 x 12.6 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1424)
  Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Color Photography; Arabic Writing; Maps; Italian Writing
- Historical map of Helwan (1888). 8.9 x 12.6 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1425)
  Color Photography; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Maps; Public Baths; Architecture
- Historical map of Helwan (1930). 12.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1426)
  Color Photography; Arabic Writing; Maps; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints
- Framed photographs of villas in Helwan. 12.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1427)
  Helwan, Egypt; Houses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Color Photography; Arabic Writing
- Framed map of Helwan (1941). 12.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1431)
  Color Photography; Photographic Prints; Maps; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Italian Writing
- Framed pictures and floor plans of Helwan monastery "Abu Qarkura". 12.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1432)
  Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Architecture; Deserts; Color Photography; Monasteries/Convents; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; English Writing
- Framed pictures, floor plans, and drawings. 8.9 x 12.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1437)
  Photographic Prints; Color Photography; Architecture; Monasteries/Convents; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Helwan, Egypt
- A headline on a newspaper clipping. 23.2 x 32.2 cm, 26 January 1930 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1451)
  Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Cairo, Egypt; Italian Writing; Printed Materials
- The Cordi Jesu Catholic church beside a car garage on Abd El-Khalik Tharwat street in Downtown Cairo. 23.2 x 32.3 cm, Circa 1930 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1452)
  Buildings; Streets/Roads; Churches; Factories; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Helwan, Egypt; Religious Sites
- The altar of the Cordi Jesu Catholic church. 32.2 x 23.3 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref1461)
  Photographic Prints; Churches; Religious Sites; Religious Crosses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Imagery; Cairo, Egypt
- Students in a classroom., 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1463)
  Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Teachers; Schools/Education; Students; Boys; Men; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Maps
- Group portrait of clergymen., 1948 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1466)
  Priests/Clergymen; Men; Italian Writing; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Facial Hair